Professional Summary

More than **12 years** of experience in leading Software Development efforts along with hands-on Application Software Development & Maintenance in Java technologies. Overall responsibility for day-to-day operations of projects, periodic reporting to all stakeholders, Project Estimation, Tracking and Delivery.

TOOLS WITH ME

Languages: Java, PL/SQL, Python(Basic)

Frameworks: Struts 1.2, EJB, Spring 2.5, Hibernate 3.0.

Web-Technologies: JSP, Servlet, HTML, JavaScript, AJAX, Web-Services (REST), AngularJS **Servers:** Apache Tomcat 8, JBoss 5 & 6, Oracle Application Server 10g (v. 10.1.2 & 10.1.3)

Development Tools: Eclipse, IReport 2.0.5, PL/SQL Developer, SVN, Maven

Database: Oracle, MS-SQL

Domains: DNMS, BFSI, B2B E-Commerce (Supply Chain Management and Logistics)

WORK EXPERIENCE (12 YEARS 6 MONTHS)

Company: Logo Infosoft Business Technology Pvt. Ltd.

SEPTEMBER 2018 - NOVEMBER 2019

Designation: Solution Specialist

Role:

Provided expert guidance to IT teams working on individual projects allocated to them. Monitored progress and conferred with development team leaders. Tracked coding and ensured individual projects were of sufficient quality. Reported to management and coordinated project goals. Performed quality checks and designed quality improvement processes for projects.

Project: VIRA - Sales Force Automation for DNMS **Duration:** September 2018 - November 2019

Team Size: 10

VIRA is a product application designed to assist the on field Sales Team in high volume FMCG market by providing the sales team with on-demand Inventory, Pricing and Invoicing, Offers and Schemes. VIRA also provides OEM and Distributors with an overview of market demands in various demographics and enables them to plan for better capacity utilization, logistical planning, and launch of new products.

Company: Indus Software Technologies Pvt. Ltd. (now Ebixcash Financial Technologies)

MAY 2007 - SEPTEMBER 2018

Designation: Technical Lead

Project: LOS 5.10

Duration: December 2017 - September 2018

Team Size: 20

LOS is a product application designed to assist a bank or financial institution by automating their lending process from Loan Originations to Disbursement.

Role:

Requirement Analysis, Solutioning and estimations for delivery time lines. Collaborate with client stakeholders for business logic implementation, unit testing and issue fixing. Drive collective team efforts for development and deployment of major business enhancements in the application. Provide support for application deployment via weekly deployment cycles on Integration and UAT environments.

anupgaikwad@gmail.com Mobile No: +91 9881737380

Skills Acquired:

Languages: JAVA (JDK 1.6), Struts 1.2, EJB, JSP and Servlet, JavaScript

Application server: JBoss 6
Database: Oracle 10g (PL/SQL)

Project: ODC for Logo Business Solutions

Client: Logo Infosoft

Duration: August 2016 - November 2017

Team Size: 4

Logo Business Solutions is a Turkey based ERP software company catering to the SME segment of the Industry.

Role:

Solutioning and Customizing client requirements in LPT (Logo Platform Tailor). Interfacing with clients for understanding business challenges. Providing estimations and delivery time lines.

Skills Acquired:

Languages: JAVA (JDK 1.6), JSP and Servlet

Web server: Apache Tomcat 6

Database: MS SQL Server Express, Oracle 10g (PL/SQL)

Tools: Eclipse, LPT framework

Project: ODC for Archway

Client: Archway Marketing Services (USA)

Duration: May 2007 - July 2016

Team Size: 17

Archway Marketing Services is the USA based Supply Chain Management Company.

Role:

Spearhead design, development, and launch of Web-based, client-facing, solutions for \$200M fulfilment services provider, leading solution development teams comprised of on- and off-shore resources. Collaborate extensively with internal project teams and client stakeholders to drive the product and solution design, development, integration, and delivery process. Ensure product quality through aggressive testing and validation, leading defect management and correction efforts. Provide exceptional post-implementation client support, training, issue response, resolution, and application enhancement.

Skills Acquired:

Languages: JAVA (JDK 1.6), Struts 1.2, JSP and Servlet

Web server: JBoss 5.1.1, Oracle Application Server 10g (v.10.1.3)

Database: Oracle 10g (PL/SQL)

Project Name: *E-Stores*

Brief Description of Project:

Customize primary fulfilment service application-EStore-modules in alignment with client requirements, enabling order placement, order history tracking, and account management.

Project Name: Web2Print

Brief Description of Project:

Designed Web-based print feature allowing PDF storage of customized print materials and multi-vendor and print requests.

Project Name: ArchPro

Brief Description of Project:

anupgaikwad@gmail.com Mobile No: +91 9881737380

ArchPro is intended to be the web application meant for generating reports, search various client information, menu management etc. The report generation is done with the help Jasper Report API and iReport Tool is used for formatting reports.

Project Name: Credit Card Service

Brief Description of Project:

Led a two-stage credit card processing project. Developed process to save credit information for manual processing as a proof-of-concept; managed a second phase to build PCI-compliant automated processing via Braintree.

Project Name: ArchAnalytics

Brief Description of Project:

Spearheaded development of interactive, dashboard-style reporting and business intelligence (BI) tools; leveraged Java, JSP, JasperReports, and IReports technologies along with extensive use of PL/SOL.

PREVIOUS EXPERIENCE (2005 JUNE TO 2007 JANUARY)

Company: aurionPro Solutions Limited. (JUNE 2005 - JAN 2007)

Designation: Software Developer (Back Office Support)

aurionPro Solutions Ltd. is a Banking software company providing various core banking solutions and back office support to leading banks in India and abroad.

Role:

Support Executive (Back Office)

Process: iDeal Migration (DBS, Singapore)

Brief Description of Project:

DBS had introduced a new system for their Corporate Customers using online services. DBS introduced a new user interface for better user experience and enhanced security using wi-fi token systems for secure log-in. We were required to contact these corporate users via phone and understand their current user profile to create a new user profile in the new system. Requirements for new users as well as old users were gathered and documented using a template provided by DBS for the migration.

ON-SITE ASSIGNMENTS

- Travelled to Singapore on Business Visa from Oct. 2005 to Nov 2005.
- Travelled to USA on Business Visa from July 2010 to August 2010.

EDUCATION

Master of Computer Management (MCM), 2006 • UNIVERSITY OF PUNE, Pune.

Bachelor of Commerce (B.Com), 2003 • University of Pune, Pune.

PERSONAL DETAILS

Date of Birth: 23rd January 1983

Address: Plot No. 4, Girish Hsg. Soc., Warje Naka (Old), Pune - 411052 Languages Known: English (Fluent), Marathi (Native), Hindi (Native)